Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
♪Blossoms rise and scatter never to return♪
♪تتفتح الأزهار وتتناثر إلى الأبد♪
♪Time rushes on toward its withering end♪
♪يمضي الزمن مسرعاً نحو نهايته المحتومة♪
♪Rights and wrongs unfold♪
تتكشف الحقائق والأخطاء
♪Breaking through fate's tightening walls♪
♪اختراق جدران القدر المتراصة♪
♪Few ever find their way home♪
♪قلما يجد أحد طريقه إلى المنزل♪
♪Through storms and drifting snow as silver hair falls♪
♪عبر العواصف والثلوج المتراكمة بينما يتساقط الشعر الفضي♪
♪A lifetime of ruin for one bitter revel♪
♪ عمرٌ من الخراب من أجل احتفالٍ مريرٍ واحد ♪
♪A single dream born from a single thought♪
♪حلم واحد ولد من فكرة واحدة♪
♪Shattered at a touch♪
♪تحطّم بلمسة♪
♪When the dream fades I look once more♪
♪عندما يتلاشى الحلم، أنظر مرة أخرى♪
=Aligned Reverence=
=احترام متناغم=
(Adapted from Jinyi's novel of the same name on Qimao Novel)
(مقتبس من رواية جيني التي تحمل نفس الاسم على موقع Qimao Novel)
=Episode 22= (I want to stand equal to heaven)
=الحلقة 22= (أريد أن أكون مساوياً للسماء)
It seems I am not the only one who wants to interrogate Prince Yu tonight.
يبدو أنني لست الوحيد الذي يريد استجواب الأمير يو الليلة.
I will go find out more.
سأذهب لأستفسر أكثر.
He is not dead, is he?
إنه ليس ميتاً، أليس كذلك؟
I knew what to do.
كنت أعرف ما يجب فعله.
Yan.
نعم.
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
Leave quickly.
غادر بسرعة.
Pretend you were never here.
تظاهر بأنك لم تكن هنا أبداً.
I am now framed as the killer who poisoned Prince Yu.
لقد تم تلفيق تهمة لي الآن بأنني القاتل الذي سمم الأمير يو.
Go now.
اذهب الآن.
Unless you explain everything, I will not leave.
لن أغادر إلا إذا شرحت لي كل شيء .
Yuan,
يوان،
the one who caused the downfall of the entire Xiao family
الشخص الذي تسبب في سقوط عائلة شياو بأكملها
is the Emperor.
هو الإمبراطور.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I knew you
كنت أعرفك
would definitely protect me.
سيحميني بالتأكيد.
You are wrong.
أنت مخطئ.
As of today,
حتى اليوم،
no one can protect you.
لا أحد يستطيع حمايتك.
Do not worry.
لا تقلق.
The Nanyue poison
سم نانيو
will ensure you have a quick death.
سيضمن لك ذلك موتاً سريعاً.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
You cannot kill me.
لا يمكنك قتلي.
You must not kill me!
لا تقتلني!
If you kill me, I will...
إذا قتلتني، فسأفعل...
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Why?
لماذا؟
Have you forgotten
هل نسيت؟
that I was the one who helped you poison our father back then?
هل تقصد أنني أنا من ساعدك في تسميم والدنا آنذاك؟
Otherwise, this throne
وإلا، فإن هذا العرش
would have belonged to Prince Duan long ago.
كانت ستؤول إلى الأمير دوان منذ زمن بعيد.
Therefore,
لذلك،
both you and the Xiao family
أنت وعائلة شياو
must die.
يجب أن يموت.
So that is the truth.
إذن هذه هي الحقيقة.
It was you
كنت أنت
who colluded with Nanyue to frame the Xiao family,
الذين تواطأوا مع نانيوي لتلفيق التهم لعائلة شياو،
wasn't it?
أليس كذلك؟
In fact,
في الحقيقة،
you had already colluded with Nanyue long ago.
لقد تواطأت مع نانيوي منذ زمن بعيد.
No wonder as soon as our Imperial Father died,
لا عجب في ذلك بمجرد وفاة والدنا الإمبراطوري،
Nanyue launched an attack.
شنت نانيوي هجوماً.
What a meticulous scheme.
يا له من مخطط دقيق!
First, you used me to eliminate the Xiao family,
أولاً، لقد استخدمتني للقضاء على عائلة شياو،
and then you used Xie Yunyan to eliminate me!
ثم استخدمتَ شي يون يان للقضاء علي!
Do you think
هل تعتقد
if I die,
إذا متُّ،
no one will know
لن يعرف أحد
about your dirty deeds?
عن أفعالك القذرة؟
I will be waiting for you in the afterlife.
سأنتظرك في الآخرة.
The Xiao family's private seal,
الختم الخاص بعائلة شياو،
the Edict of Succession...
مرسوم الخلافة...
The private seal...
الختم الخاص...
The Edict...
المرسوم...
Dare to fight me?
هل تجرؤ على قتالي؟
Xie Yunyan
شيه يونيان
poisoned Prince Yu.
قام بتسميم الأمير يو.
Prince Yu retaliated before his death
انتقم الأمير يو قبل وفاته
and wounded Xie Yunyan.
وجرح شيه يونيان.
He was captured on the spot by the guards.
تم القبض عليه في الحال من قبل الحراس.
Xie Yunyan,
شيه يونيان,
if you want the elderly, weak,
إذا كنت تريد كبار السن، الضعفاء،
women, and children of the Xiao family to live,
نساء وأطفال عائلة شياو للعيش،
confess your crime obediently.
اعترف بجريمتك بطاعة.
The Xiao family's private seal
الختم الخاص لعائلة شياو
is related to the late Emperor's Edict of Succession.
يرتبط ذلك بمرسوم الخلافة الصادر عن الإمبراطور الراحل.
That is why the Emperor caused the destruction of the entire Xiao family.
ولهذا السبب تسبب الإمبراطور في تدمير عائلة شياو بأكملها.
Yuan,
يوان،
he is the Emperor.
هو الإمبراطور.
The Xiao family cannot defeat him.
لا تستطيع عائلة شياو هزيمته.
Only if I die
فقط إذا مت
will you all be safe.
أتمنى لكم جميعاً السلامة.
Protect Grandmother and the others.
احموا جدتي والآخرين.
Go.
يذهب.
Yan,
نعم،
hiding and backing down will not help.
لن يفيد الاختباء والتراجع.
As long as the Edict of Succession remains a threat,
طالما بقي مرسوم الخلافة يشكل تهديداً،
the Emperor will never let the Xiao family go.
لن يسمح الإمبراطور لعائلة شياو بالرحيل أبداً.
What are you going to do?
ما كنت تنوي القيام به؟
Xie Yunyan,
شيه يونيان,
promise me
وعدني
you will not confess.
لن تعترف.
Stay alive.
ابقَ على قيد الحياة.
Wait for me to come back and save you.
انتظرني حتى أعود وأنقذك.
Yuan.
يوان.
(Xie Yunyan.)
(شيه يونيان.)
(I always thought it was because you acted so drastically)
(لطالما اعتقدت أن ذلك كان بسبب تصرفك بهذه القسوة)
(that in the last life)
(ذلك في الحياة الأخيرة)
(you became so cynical)
(تصبح ساخرًا جدًا)
(and chose to ruin the world.)
(واختاروا تدمير العالم.)
Slaughter all the wicked officials in court
يجب ذبح جميع المسؤولين الفاسدين في المحكمة
to honor the heroes of my Xiao family.
تكريماً لأبطال عائلة شياو.
(Now I understand,)
(الآن فهمت،)
(it was the Qing Emperor who twisted right and wrong,)
(كان إمبراطور تشينغ هو من لوّى الصواب والخطأ)
(allowing monsters and evil spirits to run rampant in this world,)
(مما يسمح للوحوش والأرواح الشريرة بالانتشار في هذا العالم،)
(making good people stepping stones and paving bones.)
(جعل الناس الصالحين بمثابة أحجار عبور ودهان للعظام.)
(But I insist on justice being served)
(لكنني أصر على تحقيق العدالة)
(and all grievances settled.)
(وتسوية جميع المظالم).
(Xie Yunyan,)
(شيه يونيان،)
(I want to set the world right.)
(أريد أن أصلح العالم.)
(Xiao Ancestral Hall)
(قاعة شياو للأجداد)
Yuan,
يوان،
why did you wake us up
لماذا أيقظتنا؟
in the middle of the night?
في منتصف الليل؟
Where is Yan?
أين يان؟
I remember you two returned together from the court.
أتذكر أنكما عدتما معاً من المحكمة.
Grandmother, Mother,
الجدة، الأم،
tonight you must leave the capital to avoid disaster.
يجب عليك مغادرة العاصمة الليلة لتجنب الكارثة.
Heir Qi will help.
سيساعدهم طاقتهم الحيوية.
Avoid disaster? What disaster are you talking about?
تجنب الكوارث؟ عن أي كارثة تتحدث؟
The Emperor
الإمبراطور
is the one who murdered the Xiao family.
هو من قتل عائلة شياو.
Tonight,
الليلة،
he is framing Yan again
إنه يدبر مكيدة ليان مرة أخرى
for poisoning Prince Yu.
لتسميم الأمير يو.
He is using the lives of everyone in the Xiao family to force Yan to confess.
إنه يستخدم حياة جميع أفراد عائلة شياو لإجبار يان على الاعتراف.
What?
ماذا؟
Mother.
الأم.
I will
أنا سوف
explain the details after I
اشرح التفاصيل بعد ذلك
rescue Yan.
إنقاذ يان.
However, this undertaking is perilous.
لكن هذه المهمة محفوفة بالمخاطر.
I can only act freely
لا أستطيع إلا أن أتصرف بحرية
once you have left.
بمجرد مغادرتك.
Saving him is urgent.
إنقاذه أمر عاجل.
This is not the time to talk.
ليس هذا هو الوقت المناسب للكلام.
Go quickly and prepare to leave.
انطلق بسرعة واستعد للمغادرة.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Yuan,
يوان،
do you already have a plan?
هل لديك خطة بالفعل؟
I want to set the world right.
أريد أن أصلح العالم.
Young Lady Su,
الشابة سو،
this is indeed shocking.
هذا أمر صادم بالفعل.
Tonight,
الليلة،
I was never here.
لم أكن هنا قط.
Is it not a little late
أليس الوقت قد فات قليلاً؟
for Your Lordship to withdraw now?
هل يحق لسيادتكم الانسحاب الآن؟
Are you trying to implicate me?
هل تحاول توريطي؟
Did Your Lordship not ask Luo
ألم تسألوا يا صاحب السعادة لوو؟
to seek justice for the Xiao family?
السعي لتحقيق العدالة لعائلة شياو؟
Therefore, saving Xie Yunyan
ولذلك، إنقاذ شيه يونيان
is something you must do.
هذا شيء يجب عليك فعله.
Su Jinyuan, are you out of your mind?
سو جينيوان، هل فقدت عقلك؟
Tell me how to save him.
أخبرني كيف أنقذه.
Are we to storm the imperial prison or raid the execution ground?
هل سنقتحم السجن الإمبراطوري أم سنداهم ساحة الإعدام؟
How many lives do you have to waste?
كم من الأرواح يجب أن تهدر؟
You know what I mean.
أنت تعرف ما أعنيه.
Naive.
ساذج.
Without a just cause,
بدون سبب عادل،
we will only become rebels scorned by the entire world.
لن نصبح إلا متمردين يحتقرهم العالم أجمع.
Tonight, I learned an earth-shattering secret.
الليلة، علمت سراً يهز كيان الأرض.
The late Emperor was killed by Prince Yu.
قُتل الإمبراطور الراحل على يد الأمير يو.
That is how the current Emperor seized his opportunity.
هكذا انتهز الإمبراطور الحالي فرصته.
In those years,
في تلك السنوات،
Prince Duan, as the crown prince,
الأمير دوان، بصفته ولي العهد،
was nonetheless kept from the throne.
ومع ذلك، فقد مُنع من الوصول إلى العرش.
I know you harbor resentment,
أعلم أنك تحمل ضغينة،
and have been secretly plotting and preparing for a long time.
وقد كانوا يخططون ويستعدون سراً لفترة طويلة.
If we have the late Emperor's Edict,
إذا كان لدينا مرسوم الإمبراطور الراحل،
and in addition,
بالإضافة إلى ذلك،
evidence of his tyrannical and unworthy actions,
دليل على أفعاله الاستبدادية وغير اللائقة،
Your Lordship,
صاحب السعادة،
will you not have a just cause to act?
ألن يكون لديك سبب وجيه للتصرف؟
Is that true?
هل هذا صحيح؟
I once promised my late husband
لقد وعدت زوجي الراحل ذات مرة
(Memorial Tablet of Xiao Jin)
(لوحة تذكارية لشياو جين)
that I would take this secret with me to my grave.
أنني سأحمل هذا السر معي إلى قبري.
Back then,
في ذلك الوقت،
my late husband, Xiao Yingting, and the late Emperor were like brothers.
كان زوجي الراحل، شياو يينغتينغ، والإمبراطور الراحل بمثابة إخوة.
At that time,
في ذلك الوقت،
the late Emperor was worried
كان الإمبراطور الراحل قلقاً
that his sons harbored ambitions for the throne.
أن أبناءه كانوا يطمحون إلى العرش.
So he prepared an Edict of Succession for the Crown Prince early on.
لذلك قام بإعداد مرسوم الخلافة لولي العهد في وقت مبكر.
It was locked in the Ancestral Temple, on the main beam.
كان مغلقاً في معبد الأجداد، على العارضة الرئيسية.
The key
المفتاح
was the private seal of Xiao family.
كان الختم الخاص بعائلة شياو.
Later, when Nanyue invaded,
وفي وقت لاحق، عندما غزت نانيوي،
the Crown Prince led the army to battle,
قاد ولي العهد الجيش إلى المعركة،
but the late Emperor suddenly passed away.
لكن الإمبراطور الراحل توفي فجأة.
By the time the Crown Prince and my late husband rushed back,
عندما عاد ولي العهد وزوجي الراحل مسرعين،
the current Emperor
الإمبراطور الحالي
had already ascended the throne.
كان قد اعتلى العرش بالفعل.
To appoint someone else at that moment
لتعيين شخص آخر في تلك اللحظة
would certainly have plunged the world into chaos.
كان من المؤكد أنه سيغرق العالم في الفوضى.
My late husband had no choice but to let the matter stand
لم يكن أمام زوجي الراحل خيار سوى ترك الأمر على حاله.
and warned me
وحذرني
to keep the matter of the Edict
للحفاظ على مسألة المرسوم
secret forever.
سرٌّ إلى الأبد.
Yet, even this could not escape the Emperor's suspicion.
ومع ذلك، حتى هذا لم يفلت من شكوك الإمبراطور.
The Xiao family
عائلة شياو
was ultimately ruined and destroyed.
لقد دُمّرت وهُدمت في نهاية المطاف.
(Memorial Tablet of Xiao Jin, Xiao Yunxi, Xiao Yunxin)
(اللوح التذكاري لشياو جين، وشياو يونكسي، وشياو يونشين)
May I ask, Grand Madam,
هل لي أن أسأل، سيدتي الكبرى؟
where is the private seal now?
أين الختم الخاص الآن؟
Yuan,
يوان،
take off your headpiece, the one symbolizing your authority over the family.
انزع غطاء رأسك، ذلك الذي يرمز إلى سلطتك على العائلة.
No wonder.
لا عجب في ذلك.
They searched everywhere but couldn't find the Xiao family's private seal.
لقد بحثوا في كل مكان لكنهم لم يتمكنوا من العثور على الختم الخاص بعائلة شياو.
It was hidden in this hairpin all along.
لقد كان مخفياً في دبوس الشعر هذا طوال الوقت.
Your Lordship,
صاحب السعادة،
now,
الآن،
are you willing to raise an army?
هل أنت مستعد لتجنيد جيش؟
♪Even the gentlest waves can never be your touch♪
♪حتى ألطف الأمواج لا يمكن أن تكون لمستك♪
♪No lighthouse waiting ever matched the way I held on♪
لم يسبق لأي منارة أن انتظرت مثل الطريقة التي تشبثت بها.
♪The harbor lies in silent moonlight♪
♪يقع الميناء في ضوء القمر الصامت♪
♪The pipes call no seabirds home♪
♪لا تنادي المزامير طيور البحر إلى موطنها♪
♪This coastal line feels barren as a wasteland♪
♪يبدو هذا الخط الساحلي قاحلاً كأرض جرداء♪
♪They laugh at those who carve their hopes into drifting boats♪
يسخرون من أولئك الذين يبنون آمالهم على قوارب تائهة.
♪Yet in my loneliest nights you never reached for me♪
♪لكن في أشد ليالي وحدتي لم تمد يدك إليّ أبداً♪
♪At the far edge of the tides I waited long for you♪
♪على أقصى حافة المد والجزر انتظرتك طويلاً♪
♪Seasons washed away by ebb and flow but still I never left♪
♪ تلاشت الفصول مع المد والجزر، لكنني لم أغادر أبدًا ♪
♪A gentle breeze slips through mirage and illusion♪
♪تتسلل نسمة لطيفة عبر السراب والوهم♪
♪Even starlight's tender message pales beside your single greeting♪
♪حتى رسالة ضوء النجوم الرقيقة تتضاءل أمام تحيتك الوحيدة♪
♪At the far edge of the tides I waited long for you♪
♪على أقصى حافة المد والجزر انتظرتك طويلاً♪
♪Longing lets the monsoon wrinkle time as I run to you♪
♪الشوق يجعل المطر يتجعد الزمن وأنا أركض إليك♪
♪Snow may turn one's hair to white yet I burn all bridges for you♪
♪قد يحوّل الثلج شعر المرء إلى اللون الأبيض، لكنني سأحرق كل الجسور من أجلك♪
♪When the sea calms after the storm I will see you turning back♪
♪عندما يهدأ البحر بعد العاصفة، سأراك تعود أدراجك♪
♪At the far edge of the tides I waited long for you♪
♪على أقصى حافة المد والجزر انتظرتك طويلاً♪
♪Seasons washed away by ebb and flow but still I never left♪
♪ تلاشت الفصول مع المد والجزر، لكنني لم أغادر أبدًا ♪
♪A gentle breeze slips through mirage and illusion♪
♪تتسلل نسمة لطيفة عبر السراب والوهم♪
♪When the sea calms after the storm I will see you turning back♪
♪عندما يهدأ البحر بعد العاصفة، سأراك تعود أدراجك♪